# John Flood

jflood215@gmail.com 802-309-0753 Indianapolis, IN https://jflood215.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-flood-developer http://github.com/jflood215

## Objective

Dietitian turned developer, looking to utilize an eagerness to learn and a passion for coding to transition into a developer or engineer role. I have 10+ years of experience collaborating and communicating on successful teams and look to bring my drive and motivation to this new career.

#### **Technical Skills**

Experienced: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Git

Knowledgeable: TypeScript, Node.js, SQL, Python, APIs, JSON, Express, Bootstrap, Material UI, Redux

#### **Education**

#### **Eleven Fifty Academy**

Full Stack Web Development Program

## Indianapolis, IN

May 2020 - Oct. 2020

24-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

# SUNY Plattsburgh Plattsburgh, NY

B.S. in Nutrition, with a minor in chemistry

# **Technical Projects**

- Created a Full Stack macro/calorie calculator and recipe API using React for the front end along with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL to build the back end. This project is currently deployed on Heroku at: <a href="https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com">https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com</a>
- Created a responsive website portfolio using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to showcase my skills to friends, family, and employers. <a href="https://jflood215.github.io">https://jflood215.github.io</a>
- A group project that utilizes Git, Typescript and React legacy code with class components along with Node.js, Express, Material UI and PostgreSQL to develop a Full Stack web app for music lovers. https://redvinyl-music.herokuapp.com

## **Professional Experience**

Noom Inc. Remote

Software Engineer Internship

Dec. 2020 – Current

- Worked on the front end of the Noom codebase as part of the growth and experiment team.
- Expanded my knowledge by working with Git, Redux, and other aspects of the Noom tech stack.
- Created an FAQ accordion dropdown using JavaScript, React, ¡Query, Redux, and CSS.

**Noom Inc.**\*\*Virtual Health Coach\*\*

Semote

July 2019 – Current

Jan 2015

Met and exceeded all expectations even as company growth exceeded 200% this year.

- Exceptional marks on all performance and transcript reviews.
- Managed a high caseload consistently and efficiently from enrollment to completion.

On Point Nutrition LLC Zionsville, IN

*Owner* Dec. 2018 – June 2020

- Created detailed and customized nutrition plans that decreased symptoms by up to 60%.
- Quantified and tracked progress through numerous metrics using a data driven approach.
- 88% of initial consults led to a follow up appointment.

Lincare Indianapolis, IN

Senior Medical Nutrition Specialist

Feb. 2009 – July 2019

- Worked as part of the highest grossing, and most successful enteral office in the company.
- Supported and managed multiple dietitians and offices in 6 states around the Midwest.
- Trained over 100 new dietitian hires on all clinical and insurance related aspects of the job.